#### ETHAN STARLING

ethan.jr.starling@gmail.com 317-509-9002 Indianapolis, IN www.linkedin.com/in/ethan-starling/

#### **Profile**

Driven, motivated software developer with experience in C#, SQL, Power BI, multi-tasking, and ASP.NET driven by 500+ hours logged of coding time and training. Exposure to HTML and CSS while applying technical and critical thinking skills gained from those experiences. A strong background in leadership and customer service provides me an advantage to manage people and deal with different customer situations in a fast-paced environment.

#### Education

- Eleven Fifty Academy, Software Development Immersive Learning Program, Indianapolis IN, May 2022
  - 12-week immersive learning program for software development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning, and 500+ hours logged of coding time and training.
- Purdue University, Bachelor of Science in Geology, West Lafayette IN, December 2015

### **Competencies & Functional Skills**

Problem solving, competent data management, multi-task management, customer service, deadline regulation, agile methodology, portfolio development, troubleshooting

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages/Libraries: C#, ASP.NET, SQL Cloud Technologies: Azure, GitHub

CI/CD: Agile, Git

Databases/ORM: Entity Framework, SQL Server, Relational Databases

Web Technologies: CSS, HTML, MVC, APIs, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Design, Power BI

**Testing Tools: MSTest** 

## **Technical Projects**

- Spongebob ASP.NET API
  - Utilized C# and swagger to build an api for the Spongebob show for characters/places/items.
- US Parks ASP.NET MVC Web application
  - Utilized HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap 4, and C# to design a mvc web application that allows the user to look up specific state and national parks and see the various attractions and nature within them.
- Several Business Console applications
  - Utilized C# to construct several console applications pertaining to the logic of business's requests.

### **Professional Experience**

# Veratas, Noida Uttar Pradesh, India-Remote (July 2022 - Present)

- Software development internship that aims to develop skills in SQL and Power BI while working on projects Fresh Thyme Market, Carmel IN (2016 Present)
- Food preparation, quality control, customer service, training/mentoring of new employees

## Ford Dining Court, Purdue University, West Lafayette IN (2012 - 2015)

- Collaborated with cooks to serve meals in streamlined procedure, trained new employees, worked while in school Camp Kikthawenund, Frankton IN (2008 2011)
- Served as a primary lifeguard/swimming instructor and educated Webelos scouts on outdoor camping and safety

### **Accomplishments**

EFA Integrity Core Value Award | Eagle Scout